(CLANGING)
(DRAWER CLOSES)
(INAUDIBLE)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
BEN: (ON PHONE)
Michelle, please don't hang up.
Just talk to me, okay?
I can't believe you just left.
Michelle.
Come back.
Please say something.
Michelle, talk to me.
Look, we had an argument.
Couples fight.
That is no reason to
just leave everything behind.
Running away isn't gonna help it any.
Michelle, please...
(DIALTONE)
NEWCASTER: More details on that.
Elsewhere today,
power has still not been restored
to many cities on the southern seaboard
in the wake of this afternoon's
widespread blackout.
While there had been some
inclement weather in the region,
the problem seems linked to
what authorities are calling
a catastrophic power surge
that has crippled traffic in the area.
- (LOUD CRASH)
- (GRUNTS)
- (TYRES SCREECHING)
- (SCREAMS)
- (GLASS SHATTERING)
- (GASPING)
(GROANS)
(HORN HONKING)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(SNIFFS)
(SIGHS)
(GASPING)
(CHAINS RATTLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(SOBS) No.
(CHAIN JANGLING)
No! (SOBBING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Damn.
(CLATTERS)
(GRUNTS)
(RUMBLING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
(DOOR CREAKING)
Okay. Okay, please.
Please.
Please don't hurt me.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Please.
Just let me go, okay?
I won't tell anybody.
I promise, okay?
Please just let me go. Please.
MAN: You need fluids.
You were in shock.
What are you going to do to me?
I'm going to keep you alive.
Work on getting handy with these.
My boyfriend was expecting me.
He'll send the cops looking.
I'm sorry.
But no one is looking for you.
(CLANGS)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS SOFTLY)
(EXHALES)
(SCRAPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SIGHS)
(COUGHING)
(FIRE ALARM BEEPING)
(RAPID FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(DOOR OPENS)
- (GASPS)
- (GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
(MAN CLEARS THROAT)
(GASPS)
You've got some fight in you.
I can respect that.
But don't even think
about trying that again.
You're lucky to be here at all.
And my generosity only extends so far.
Eggs.
Toradol to help with your pain.
Please.
Please, just let me go. Please.
There is nowhere to go, Michelle.
I looked through your wallet.
Given as how I saved your life,
I think that's acceptable.
You're lucky to be here at all.
What do you mean?
I found you, and I saved your
life by bringing you here.
I don't understand. I...
(SIGHING)
There's been an attack.
What?
An attack. A big one.
I'm not sure yet if
it's chemical or nuclear,
but down here, we're safe.
- And where are we exactly?
- Underneath my farmhouse.
Forty miles outside of Lake Charles.
I was driving north of here.
You were in an accident.
You were turned over
on the side of the road.
I was driving by and I saw...
I saved your life, Michelle.
I couldn't just leave you there.
(SOFTLY) Okay.
Well,
thank you so much
for saving my life.
I guess I should go to a hospital now.
You can't leave.
An attack means fallout.
Which contaminates
the air above ground.
(STUTTERS)
That's how it works.
How long do we have
to wait until it's safe?
Depends on the proximity
of the closest blast.
One year, maybe two.
(HOWARD SIGHS)
And that's if we're talking
about weapons that we know of.
Russians are developing
some nasty stuff.
And if the Martians finally
figured out a way to get here,
their weapons will make the Russkies'
look like sticks and stones.
Luckily,
I've prepared for this.
(SOFTLY) Right.
Well, I'll need to use your phone then
to call my family and
tell them that I'm safe here
and make sure they're okay.
Michelle, they're not okay.
(HOWARD SIGHS)
How do you know that?
Everyone outside of here is dead.
But what about you?
Don't you have a family?
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
Who's that?
Excuse me.
HOWARD: (SHOUTS)
What did you do?
(LOUD THUDDING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(GASPS)
You know what, Michelle?
I'm gonna tell you what I told him.
You need to eat, you need to sleep,
and you need to start showing
me a little bit of appreciation.
My name is Howard, by the way.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(DOOR LOCKS)
(VEHICLE ENGINE STARTS)
(VEHICLE DRIVES AWAY)
(MUSIC PLAYING IN DISTANCE)
- (CLATTERS)
- (GASPS)
Oh, God! Oh, shit.
I'm sorry.
(CHUCKLES)
(GROANS SOFTLY)
I'm sorry about that.
Uh, I didn't mean to scare you.
Are you, um...
Here. You hungry?
So, how are you doing?
You okay?
- What is this?
- It's a bunker.
Your room's a little bit of a fixer-upper,
but at least you got a door.
A scary door, but you still got a door.
How long have you been down here?
Couple of days, I think.
You know,
it's actually kind of hard to tell
with no windows or sunlight
or anything. (CHUCKLES)
(WHISPERS) I mean,
how do we get out of here?
Oh, he didn't tell you?
About...
Getting out of here is the
last thing you want to do.
Because the air up there,
it's contaminated.
HOWARD: I see you've met Emmett.
What happened to him?
He did that to himself.
And his stumbling around
isn't helping anything.
What you heard earlier,
was him knocking over a shelf
with a whole week's worth of food,
which he's sorry for, correct?
Totally.
Let's go. Bathroom time.
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
HOWARD: This is the common area.
Good for R & R.
As you can see,
I've planned for a long stay.
The aquaponics system
cleans the air and keeps it fresh.
This is the living room.
Help yourself to any reading.
If you like to watch films,
I have some on DVD and VHS cassette.
Just make sure you put them back
in their sleeve when they're done.
The kitchen's fully functional.
Has an electric stove,
refrigerator, freezer, silverware.
And that table's a family heirloom,
which means watch your glasses.
Always use coasters and placemats.
Keep your hands to yourself!
Understand?
No touching.
Take a seat.
This way.
This is my private space.
Off-limits, unless
I give express permission.
Go ahead.
- I don't need to.
- You will, though.
And I've got to pace
these things out, so please.
I need privacy.
You're welcome to close the curtain.
I can't with you standing there.
And I can't trust you
not to burn this place down.
This is for my own safety.
I'm not some pervert! Just go.
(SIGHING)
HOWARD: Don't flush
unless you've gone!
We can't afford wasted flushes.
Take a seat. Are you hungry?
- Those are Megan's.
- (VESSELS CLANG)
She never went anywhere
without two or three of those things.
Who's Megan?
Megan's not with us anymore.
(FAINT WHIRRING)
Don't worry. Just the generator.
Maybe it's a car outside.
(SCOFFS)
That's not possible.
I heard one earlier. Above my room.
If you had heard a car,
the driver would be long dead by now.
Well, shouldn't we at least try
to call the police or someone
to find out what actually happened?
There's no one left to call.
See that? Nothing's coming through.
(HOWARD EXHALES DEEPLY)
You think I sound crazy.
I mean, it's amazing. You people...
You wear helmets
when you ride your bikes.
You have seat belts in your cars.
You have alarm systems
to protect your homes.
But what do you do
when those alarms go off?
"Crazy" is building your ark
after the flood has already come!
I think maybe it's time
you met Frank and Mildred.
(KEYS JANGLING)
Closest I could get to an airlock.
- (GASPING)
- See?
What happened to them?
They weren't as lucky as you.
It's the air, Michelle.
That's what happens
when you get exposed.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(TYRES SQUEALING)
(CRASHING)
I keep this door sealed at all times.
No one comes in or out.
EMMETT: Met Frank and Mildred, huh?
It's funny, right?
The whole world ends
and the thing he's most upset about
is a pair of dead pigs?
You in need of some reading material?
I took all the quizzes. Sorry.
But I did learn
how to do a French braid, so,
you know, if you want me
to do that for you, just let me know.
What do you know about him?
He was in the Navy, I know that.
I guess he did, uh,
some stuff with satellites.
What kind of stuff?
Satellite stuff.
Well, what brought him out here?
I'm not sure.
He bought this property a while back.
But I never paid much attention
till he hired me to help
him get this place set up.
The work was entertaining, though,
that's for sure. (CHUCKLES)
You know, Howard's like a black
belt in conspiracy theory.
Plus, you know, how often
do you get hired to help build
a doomsday bunker?
So, he didn't
kidnap you?
(SCOFFS) No!
What about your arm?
Weren't you trying to escape?
I was trying to get in.
I watched Howard build this place,
piece by piece, for years.
He was always talking about,
you know, possible attacks from
Al Qaeda, Russia, South Korea.
You mean North Korea.
(STUTTERS)
Is that the crazy one?
So, yeah, that one.
And, uh, you know,
poured all his money into this place.
Took to it like his life depended on it.
Which, you know,
that stays with you.
So...
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
He told you all this
while you're building his bomb shelter.
And now he says that
the air is contaminated
and everybody's dead.
Yeah, I know what you're getting at,
but there's more to it.
Howard abducted me.
He drove me off the road
and he dragged me here.
So, whatever he's telling you
about the air, some big attack,
the purpose of this shelter, is a lie.
No. No way.
The attack, I saw it myself.
What do you mean?
I was on my way home from work.
And it looked like a flash.
Bright red.
Like an explosion, from way far off.
It wasn't like fireworks.
Naw, this was more like
something you'd read about in the Bible.
So, what, you saw, what,
a flash of light? Lightning?
A fire that flared up?
I'm not explaining it right.
This wasn't like anything I'd ever seen.
And so, my first thought
was to come here.
And when I got here,
Howard was closing the door.
And I could see it,
right there on his face,
he knew something was happening.
Something bad.
And so, I fought my way in.
I heard a car.
Right here. Above us.
You heard someone?
Right above us.
That isn't possible.
- The air is...
- What, contaminated?
- How do you know that?
- Because I told him.
Dinner's ready.
I see you two are getting along.
Hmm.
How's that sauce?
It's fine.
As cooks go, I'm okay.
Not great, but okay.
Megan was a good cook.
You'll learn to love cooking.
Mmm...
EMMETT: Mmm.
It's delicious.
That's the best sauce I've ever tasted.
Are you being funny?
No, I mean,
considering the alternative,
which is, you know,
getting burnt up in a chemical attack,
or nuclear,
I'd say being alive and down here would
make a fried turd taste pretty good, so...
Best damn sauce I ever had.
That's not a bad point.
And, please,
watch your language at table.
Right?
You know what I haven't been able to
get out of my head, for some reason?
Ever since I got down here.
Tattoos.
Always wanted one.
But I never got any.
'Cause everybody always said,
"No, no, Emmett, you'll never get
a decent job if you do that."
Whatever.
Like that matters now, right?
Tell you what,
if I had known this was coming,
I would've gotten, like,
50 of them. I swear, man.
I would look like a circus freak,
or something.
I'd just be covered head to toe.
Tattoos all over my...
You know, everywhere. Face?
Sure. Right there.
Across my forehead.
Just my name. "Emmett."
Or, you know,
- "Thug Life."
- (CHUCKLES)
"YOLO."
I don't even know what that means,
but, you know,
I hear people saying it all the time,
so, it must be cool.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, what about you, Howard?
Anything you wish you'd done?
In all honesty, no.
No?
No crazy nights in Vegas?
Maybe, uh, take a pilgrimage to Waco?
Everything I wanted to do, I did.
I focused on being prepared.
And I was.
And here we are.
EMMETT: Oh, my goodness.
Is that Monopoly?
There we go!
Yeah, that's how we kill the time.
What would you say, Howard,
we're gonna be down here,
what, like, a year? Two? Maybe?
I bet you if we started a game right now,
we might even get halfway
finished by the time...
Stop talking!
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
You don't need to make jokes about
how long we're going to be down here
when nobody knows
how long that's going to be.
Your humor is not funny.
I don't appreciate it
while I'm trying to eat,
and neither does Michelle.
Now, please shut up
and let us eat in peace.
Hmm.
Emmett?
Would you pass me a napkin?
Thank you.
I know what you're saying.
I never could finish Monopoly.
That game really
does take forever, right?
For me, though, it was, um...
Chutes and Ladders,
uh...
Sorry!,
and Trouble.
You know, the thing with the dice
and the thing that you pressed,
- what was that called?
- The...
BOTH: Pop-O-Matic bubble! Yeah.
Did you ever play that, um...
What was that, Operation?
- Loved Operation!
- I'm telling you, man,
I couldn't play that game.
- It terrified me.
- Why...
That noise that thing would make
when you hit that edge. I mean...
- Good Lord!
- (CHUCKLING) It was pretty scary.
Could you hand me the salt?
Please?
Ah, shoot! I'm sorry.
I'm gonna need the pepper also.
What exactly do you think you're doing?
I'm asking for pepper.
Like hell you were! What was that?
I don't know what you're
talking about, Howard.
Are you trying to insult me?
Here, in the shelter that
I built that's keeping you alive?
You don't think I see what you just did?
Is that how you thank
me for saving your life?
- Howard, calm down.
- Shut up!
Shut up and stay in your seat!
Is it?
Now, let me tell you,
I know what a traitor looks like.
Understand?
I have shown you nothing,
but generosity and hospitality.
I want you to apologize.
To tell me you're going to behave.
I will.
You will what?
I'll behave.
And I'm so sorry.
HOWARD: Sit.
(HOWARD SIGHING)
Ah...
Have to stay hydrated.
Hmm.
That's easy to forget down here.
What's wrong?
(SOFTLY) Nothing.
Where are my keys?
(RUMBLING)
(SCREAMS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- Michelle!
- (GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
Michelle! Stop!
Give me those keys!
- MICHELLE: Come on.
- HOWARD: No! Don't!
(MICHELLE PANTING)
Stop!
No! No, don't! Don't!
Don't open that door!
(PANTING)
There's a car!
- There's a car! I see a car!
- HOWARD: No!
Here! Here! Here!
HOWARD: Michelle,
listen to me, don't do this!
- (THUDS)
- (GASPS)
Oh, God! Thank God!
- There's a woman.
- WOMAN: Open the door!
(STUTTERING) It's okay.
I just want to come inside.
She looks hurt.
She wants me to let her in.
Do not let her in!
- Look at her face, Michelle!
- No!
No, no, no!
No!
Oh, my God, I'm fine.
I really am fine.
- No, please, I'm okay.
- There's...
It really only...
It only touched me a little. A little!
So, could you open the door? Open it!
- She's begging me.
- You can't help her!
No one can!
Let me in. I'll be okay.
I'll be okay.
It really hardly touched me at all.
- Open the door!
- HOWARD: Don't listen to her!
God! Open the door, you bitch!
Let me in!
Let me in! Let me in!
You!
You! You! You!
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
(WHIMPERS)
(GRUNTS)
(KEYS JANGLING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(GRUNTS)
I know it's hard,
realizing they're all gone.
The ones you love.
I have something to confess to you.
(GULPS)
I crashed into your car.
Your accident
was my fault.
When I found out about
the incoming attack,
I got frantic.
I knew I needed to get back
here as soon as possible,
so I was driving like a maniac.
(SIGHS)
I tried to pass you,
and
I'm the reason you went off the road.
I mean, I know I seem
like a sensible guy,
but at the time, I wasn't myself.
It was an accident, but it was my fault.
I was afraid to tell you,
and,
I'm sorry.
Um...
You should shower.
Even the smallest amount of air
that came through the hinges
could be toxic.
These were Megan's.
If you want.
I recognized that woman's car.
Her name was Leslie, I think.
You knew her?
She was a neighbor.
Emmett wasn't the only one
who knew about this place.
If any others somehow survived,
they could be coming here, too.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
As of Friday, kindness and
generosity are antiquated customs.
I'm going to need some stitches.
What? You want me to...
This is your doing, isn't it?
I mean, I don't think I'm really qualified.
I'll walk you through it.
Here.
Have a drink.
What is it?
Technically, it's vodka.
(SLURPING)
Ah! It's safe. I distilled it myself.
(SLURPS AND COUGHS)
I just said I distilled it,
I didn't say anything about it
actually tasting good.
- Yeah, that's awful.
- You want it on the rocks?
Little trick I taught myself
as a young man
stationed on a ship
with way too much free time.
Every now and again,
if the C.O. was working us too hard,
we'd freeze and snap the knob off
the bathroom door
while he was still inside.
It usually took him an
hour or two to get out.
- I'm good.
- Suit yourself. Cheers.
Ah...
This is clean.
All you need to do is stitch.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(WINCES)
(HOWARD GASPS)
You're doing fine.
HOWARD: Some stuff
I grabbed from your car.
I didn't have time
to bring in the booze. Sadly.
What is all that?
I wanted to design clothes.
No wonder you were so good
with the stitches.
Megan wanted to be an artist.
She was your daughter?
Yes.
She was smart.
Loved to read.
The magazines were just for fun.
She inhaled books. Anything with Paris.
She liked their movies,
their culture, you know.
We used to have this little joke.
Every once in a while I'd ask her,
"What do you want to be
when you grow up?"
You know what she'd say?
"French." (CHUCKLES)
Anyway, her mother
turned her against me.
Took her off to Chicago.
People are strange creatures.
You can't always convince them
that safety is in their own best interest.
You don't know they're gone.
Anyway, at least I tried to help them.
- EMMETT: Hey.
- (KNOCKING ON WALL)
There was nothing
you could've done for that woman.
Even if you let her in,
she still would've died.
You asked earlier about regrets?
Yeah, I've got some of those.
Welcome to the club.
(SCOFFS)
I mean,
I lived my life in a 40-mile radius.
And that was by design.
I made sure that happened.
I was so fast in high school,
I even managed to outrun
my bad grades.
I was All-State track
three years in a row.
(SNIFFLES AND CLICKS TONGUE)
Caught a full ride to Louisiana Tech,
up there in Ruston.
(CHUCKLES)
I remember I spent
the last two weeks of that summer
showing off the bus ticket they sent me
to anybody who'd take a look at it.
And then came the night before
I was supposed to leave.
And I just got so worried
about how bad I was gonna do up there
with all those smart kids.
So, I went out of my way
to get just piss-wasted so bad
that I knew there was no chance
I was waking up in the morning.
So, I missed the bus.
And I didn't buy a
ticket for the next one.
Or the one after that.
Well, if you'd gone,
you might be dead now.
(CHUCKLING)
Yeah, lucky me, right?
Lucky us.
(STUTTERS)
A few years ago,
I was at a hardware store.
And there was this little
girl with her dad.
And he was in a hurry,
and she wasn't keeping up.
So, he kept
yanking on her arm.
But really hard, you know?
Too hard.
I know that feeling.
When my dad got that way,
my brother Colin was always there
to take the worst of it
for me.
And I thought, seeing this little girl,
I thought maybe I could do that
for her.
But I just kept watching.
And they're about to leave,
and I've done nothing.
And she slips.
And it throws him off-balance,
and he hits her.
And I wanted so badly to do something
to help her, but...
I did what I always do
when things get hard.
I just panicked and ran.
(SCOFFS)
(SNIFFLES)
Look, we're here.
We're alive.
And that means something.
It's gotta.
(SIGHS)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(MAN ULULATING ON TV)
(MAN SCREAMING ON TV)
- You've got to be kidding me.
- What?
We're missing pieces here.
Look at this poor cat.
He's been deformed. He's got one eye.
He's about to go snorkeling
and everything, too.
What are you doing?
Ooh!
Cornering the market on
post-apocalyptic fashion, huh?
Mmm-hmm.
You need more axes and chain saws.
For what? She has a shotgun.
Yeah. But what if up there it's like...
What? Lumberjacks?
Zombies.
Though even Howard doesn't
think that one's plausible.
But you should hear his theory
about mutant space worms.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(RUMBLING)
What is that? Howard!
Stay calm. We're okay.
(RUMBLING AND CLANGING)
- What was that?
- Quiet.
That sounds like helicopters.
HOWARD: Could be military.
But not ours.
- EMMETT: How can you tell?
- Fourteen years in the Navy.
What's happening up there?
My guess?
Those flashes that kicked this all off?
That was phase one.
Take out your opponent's
population centers
with big hits, all at once, fast.
And then for round two,
ground sweeps.
A satellite log showed an increase
in coded traffic recently.
Possibly extraterrestrial signals.
I bet what we just heard
were airborne patrols
sent to hunt down
the remaining signs of life.
Like us.
- (SOFT WHIRRING)
- (ALARM BUZZING)
Okay. Oh, boy.
That's bad.
(GRUNTS)
And that's worse.
What's up there?
Air filtration system.
I can't... (GRUNTS)
Something blocking the hatch.
If we can't get it back on, we're
gonna run out of breathable air fast.
(HOWARD GRUNTS)
You're the only one
small enough to reach it.
Reach what?
The filtration system.
Through there, the main duct.
Someone needs to get in there
and restart it.
Give me a hand.
Let me go. She's not gonna
know her way around the unit.
You won't fit. Plus your arm.
She'll be fine.
Now, to restart the unit,
you just swing the handle off,
then on, off, then on.
That should do it.
And neither of us will be able to
go in and help you if you get stuck.
Don't get stuck.
(GRUNTING SOFTLY)
HOWARD: Michelle!
Everything okay up there?
It looks like a dead end.
HOWARD: That's the incline.
Climb up that and you're almost there.
Ah, this sucks.
(GRUNTING)
(WHIRRING)
(SIGHING)
EMMETT: What's wrong?
(WHISPERS) Howard.
He lied, he lied about Megan.
What do you mean?
I think he did something horrible to her.
No, his family moved
to Chicago years ago.
What's this?
Is that blood?
Here, come with me.
Wait, that... That's not Megan.
What do you mean?
Yeah. Her name is Brittany.
I remember her.
She went to high school
with my little sister.
She...
She went missing. Two years back.
It was on the news and everything.
Most people just thought
she skipped town.
There was a message up there.
It said "Help."
It was scratched
on the inside of the window.
And this earring...
This earring was with it.
Did she ever show back up
after she went missing?
He said to me... He said to my face,
that this was his daughter.
He said this was Megan.
- He took her and he killed her.
- (CLATTERING)
(WHISPERS)
All right, let's just think.
Maybe we take away his gun.
Tie him up, get him to confess
to whatever it is he's done.
Confess to who? The police?
Look, like I said,
we can't be the only survivors, right?
The woman,
she was able to get around, right?
At least a little.
Yeah, until she died.
Directly above us,
making choking noises.
Of all the people to save us...
HOWARD: Now, that was
a great example of teamwork.
Very well done. I feel like some music.
(PUNCHING BUTTONS)
Problem solving always puts me
in a musical mood.
(CHEERFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
Michelle,
you should go shower, just in case.
Sure.
(CHEERFUL MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(SHOWER RUNNING)
I think I might have an idea.
"Ten Better Ways to Style My Bangs"?
No, not the article. This.
I think I can only make one,
but it's a start.
No kidding.
What are you doing up?
I didn't wake you up yet.
MAN: Well, I'm fixing your breakfast.
One egg over medium.
Hey, Howard.
What is this?
You re-watching Sixteen Candles?
Pretty in Pink.
It was one of Megan's favorite movies.
Can I help you with something?
No.
No, I'm just grabbing some water.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(MOVIE CONTINUES PLAYING)
Say, um...
You know, I was just thinking...
(CLEARS THROAT)
Not that I'm trying to tell you
how to run this place or anything.
I'm just a little curious.
Michelle...
Say, how close do you think she got
to that air filtration unit?
You think she touched it?
Yeah, I'm pretty sure she touched it.
Well, I know she cleaned up
after and everything,
but I'm just thinking,
given that unit filters
God knows what through from outside,
if she tracked anything back in with her,
it'd be pretty concentrated.
And, I mean, it could be
all over the shower and the sink
in your bathroom, right now.
Anyway, it's just a thought.
(MOVIE RESUMES PLAYING)
(SHUTS TV OFF)
EMMETT: Not bad so far, partner.
MICHELLE: If Howard finds this,
he's gonna kill us.
All right, so,
we get the gun away from him.
All right. We tie him up,
make sure he isn't going anywhere.
And then one of us just
goes out and looks for help.
(SIGHS)
(TIMER TICKING)
Um...
First word.
Uh...
Tiny.
Small. Pygmy. Um...
- Little.
- Yep! Mmm-hmm.
All right, uh, second word.
Ooh! Michelle is a...
(STAMMERING)
A girl.
(STAMMERING CONTINUES)
A girl. A child. Um...
(GRUNTS)
A girl.
No, she's older, see, so she is a...
"Little Princess"?
(TIMER RINGING)
Um... No, it was woman.
Um, Little Women.
Wow. Little woman.
(SIGHS)
(SNORTS)
Next time,
try being a little more specific.
Let's see here.
(TIMER STARTS TICKING)
I'm always watching.
Always.
Um...
God.
I go wherever I want.
Uh...
I mean... Well, I don't know.
I know what you're doing.
I see what you're doing.
Um...
I know what you're up to.
(STAMMERING) Look, Howard,
I don't know what you're getting at, but...
I see you when you're sleeping.
I know what you're doing,
and I'm always watching.
Always watching!
I'm always watching!
Santa Claus!
(CHUCKLES)
You're Santa Claus.
(TIMER RINGING)
Yeah, Michelle, that's great.
Except it was Emmett's turn.
Sorry, I just got a little excited.
Yeah, well, I'm keeping that point.
Totally. You earned it.
(TAPPING PEN)
(FOOTSTEPS)
Emmett?
(SHRIEKS)
Hey.
I need your help with something.
Sure.
You.
On deck.
What is this?
HOWARD: The barrel.
What's in it?
Move it into the bathroom.
HOWARD: This is perchloric acid.
Do either of you know what that is?
It's usually produced as a precursor
to ammonium perchlorate,
a fuel
used for launching
naval satellites into orbit.
It's highly corrosive.
Dissolves most biological
material on contact.
With humans, right down to the bone.
Hey, Howard, uh,
what are you showing this to us for?
You think I'm an idiot?
EMMETT: Uh...
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Howard, please,
you're gonna have to tell us
what it is that you're talking about.
I'm talking about
getting rid of some waste.
Tell me what you two
were doing with these.
You tell me what you two
were planning, right now!
Howard, listen, just take it easy.
Take it easy.
Howard, come on, please.
No. I'm giving you one chance.
EMMETT: Hey.
Howard, just calm down.
One chance to answer with
some dignity, or I swear to God,
you're going into this barrel
while you're alive to feel it.
It was me.
All right? Not her. It's just me.
- No, no, no, we...
- Stay out of this, all right?
She doesn't have a clue
what you're talking about.
I wanted your gun.
And so, I was thinking
about making a weapon
to get it from you.
I want her to respect me
the way that she respects you.
I'm not saying that I was right, okay?
And I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
I'm sorry.
I accept your apology.
(SIGHS)
(INAUDIBLE)
Listen to me.
You heard him. You heard him.
He was making a weapon.
He was gonna hurt us.
He was gonna hurt you. And it's okay.
This was the way
it was always supposed to be.
You're safe.
Now it's just you and me.
It's okay, you know.
You should go to your room now.
This next part isn't something
you need to see.
Okay.
Go on.
(SNIFFLES)
(SIGHING)
HOWARD: Michelle?
Hey.
I thought we'd change things up tonight
and have dessert before dinner.
After all,
we can do whatever we want now.
Would you like a cone or a bowl?
Megan always wanted hers in a bowl.
She said the cones were too messy.
I know that this isn't
the life you'd prefer,
that it isn't easy for
you living down here,
but I want us to be a happy family.
You and me.
The mess is all taken care of.
So, just hang loose
and I'll go get dinner started.
HOWARD: Michelle?
(DOOR OPENS)
Everything all right?
Yeah, I was just about
to do some reading.
Hmm.
It's time to set the table.
Supper's ready.
Yeah.
Okay.
(METALLIC CLANK)
It keeps doing that.
(STUTTERING) I don't know why.
Michelle, why is this loose?
- Get up.
- Why?
- Get off the mattress now!
- (GROANS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Oh, shit!
Michelle!
Stop! Goddamn it, get back here!
(PANTING)
(GASPING)
HOWARD: You gonna walk out on me?
After I saved you and kept you safe,
this is how you repay me.
No.
This is. (GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
(HOWARD GROANING)
(HOWARD WHEEZING)
(FIRE ALARM BUZZING)
(GROWLING)
(PANTING)
(YELPS)
HOWARD: Michelle!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
(HOWARD GROANING LOUDLY)
(GRUNTS)
- Stop!
- (YELPS)
You don't know what's out there.
You can't run from them!
(GRUNTS)
HOWARD: Stay with me!
Let me go!
(HOWARD SCREAMS)
(MICHELLE COUGHING)
(COUGHING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(HISSING)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(RIPPING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING FRANTICALLY)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(WHIMPERING)
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
(WHIRRING IN DISTANCE)
(MUFFLED EXPLODING)
- (EXPLODING)
- (GASPS)
Oh, come on.
(ALARM WAILING)
(PANTING)
(ALARM CONTINUES)
(SHUDDERING)
(RUSTLING)
(THUDDING)
(GRUNTS)
(ALARM CONTINUES WAILING)
(SNARLS)
Keys, keys, keys.
Come on, damn it!
- (THUDS ON DOOR)
- (GASPS)
(THUDDING)
(GASPS)
(SQUEAKING)
(PANTING)
Come on. Come on.
(ALIEN CHITTERING)
(CAR ALARM BEEPS)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(ALIEN CHITTERING)
Help! I'm out here! Help!
(RUMBLING)
(HISSING)
(PANTING)
(SNARLING)
- (GRUNTING)
- (CHITTERING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SCREAMS)
Oh, God.
(RUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
(SNARLS)
(GROWLS)
(EXPLODING)
(SCREAMING)
(SIGHS)
(GLASS CLINKING)
(PANTING)
Oh, fuck.
(ENGINE SPUTTERS)
(ENGINE SPUTTERS AND STARTS)
(TYRES SCREECHING)
(STATIC ON RADIO)
FEMALE BROADCASTER: The military
has taken back the southern seaboard.
If you are hearing this
and aren't in a safe zone,
head north of Baton Rouge.
But if you have any medical
training or combat experience,
we need help.
There are people in Houston.
There are survivors at Mercy Hospital.
Please help.
Repeat. There are people in
Houston who need our help.
Come join us.
We've taken back the southern seaboard.
And we're winning.
But if you have any medical training
or combat experience,
there are survivors...
(TYRES SQUEALING)
(RUMBLING)